Guide to the Records of the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission 1905-1913 (Bulk 1909-1911) MS 314
New-York Historical Society
Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission records
1905-1913 (Bulk 1909-1911)
New-York Historical Society
Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission
MS 314
20 Linear feet in 42 boxes
The Records of the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission focus on the commission's role in orchestrating the Hudson-Fulton Celebration of 1909. The collection contains correspondence, contracts, vouchers, cancelled checks, financial and legal documents, meeting minutes, clippings, and ephemera.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission, 1911.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Historical Note
The Hudson-Fulton Celebration was held September 25 - October 11, 1909 to commemorate the 300th anniversary of Henry Hudson discovering the Hudson River in 1609 and the 100th anniversary of the first commercial steamboat service, started by Robert Fulton in 1607. Communities along the River observed the celebration, with events occurring from Staten Island to Cohoes, New York.
In 1905, George B. McClellan, Mayor of New York City, and Francis W. Higgins, Governor of New York, appointed a committee of approximately 150 citizens to plan and implement a Hudson tercentennial celebration. The Mayor also formed a committee to plan a celebration honoring Fulton's contributions to the Hudson River region. In 1906, it was decided to merge the two committees and through the enactment of Chapter 325 of the Laws of 1906, the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission was formed on April 27, 1906.
The commission was divided into several working committees, the number increasing from 12 in the first year to 51 by the time the celebration commenced. Some of these committees were the Aquatic Sports Committee, Auditing Committee, Historical and Carnival Parades Committee, Invitations Committee, Medal Committee, Naval Parade Committee, Plan and Scope Committee, Reception Committee, and Religious Services Committee.
The New York State government appropriated about 48 percent of the funds required for the celebration, while the New York City government contributed about 24 percent of the funds. Since the federal government did not provide financial aid for the celebration, nor did any other state governments, the remaining 28 percent of required funds came from private donations made to a subscription fund set up by the commission.
The celebration was intended to not only commemorate two significant historical achievements, but also encourage "civic pride," start a "historical awakening," "assimilate" the immigrant population, and promote "international friendship" and world peace. Dignitaries from throughout the world were invited to participate, and visitors filled New York hotels beyond capacity. The celebration included banquets and receptions, various parades throughout the city, aquatic competitions, and naval parades among other festivities. Wilbur Wright was hired to perform several aerial demonstrations during the celebration, flying along the Hudson River from Governor's Island to Grant's Tomb. Upon its conclusion, the Hudson-Fulton Celebration was described as a "jubilee of happiness," whereby New York enjoyed two weeks of peace, patriotism, and prosperity.
Scope and Content Note
The Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission Records document the activities of the Commission from 1905 to 1913. The bulk of the material is from 1909 to 1911, the time in which most of the preparation and follow-up activities occurred. While the Invitation Replies subseries, as well as a few pieces of correspondence, do discuss the event's success, most of the collection focuses on preparation activites and the Commission's inner workings, rather than the celebration itself. However, The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission offer a detailed account of the Celebration, as well as insight on the event's successes.
The bulk of the collection is composed of correspondence and financial documents, particularly payment vouchers. The collection also contains legal documents, organizational materials, clippings, ephemera, and assorted materials unrelated to the Hudson-Fulton Celebration. There is very little visual material, as most of this is housed in the Print Room's collection (see Related Material).
Arrangement
The records are divided into 12 series:
Missing Title
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Financial Documents
Series III: Legal Documents
Series IV: Organizational Materials
Series V: Ephemera
Series VI: Clippings
Series VII: The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission
Series VIII: Materials unrelated to the Hudson-Fulton Celebration
Related Material at The New-York Historical Society
Hudson-Fulton Celebration Collection (PR-268)
The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission, 1909 (BobCat call number: F127.H82 H53 1910)
Account books.; Accounts.; Acknowledgements.; Address books.; Annual reports.; Audits; Blueprints (reprographic copies); Cashbooks.; Checks (bank checks); Checkbooks; Clippings (information artifacts); Drafts (documents); Letters (correspondence); Contracts.; Ledgers (account books); Minutes (administrative records); Minute books.; Ephemera.; Inventories; Invitations.; Payroll records.; Legal documents.; Obituaries; Scrapbooks.; Souvenir programs.; Tickets.; Visiting cards; Vouchers.; New York (N.Y.) -- 1900-1910.; Centennial celebrations, etc. -- New York (State) -- New York.; Hudson-Fulton Celebration, 1909.; Fulton, Robert, 1765-1815 -- Centennial celebrations, etc.; Hall, Edward Hagaman, 1858-1936; Hudson, Henry, -1611 -- Centennial celebrations, etc.; McClellan, George B. (George Brinton), 1865-1940; Ridder, Herman, 1851-1915; Sackett, Henry Woodward, 1853-1929; Seligman, Isaac Newton, 1855-1917; Woodford, Stewart L. (Stewart Lyndon), 1835-1913; Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission -- Archives.
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries I.A. General Correspondence
    Scope and Contents note
    This subseries contains both the internal and external correspondence of the Commission. While most of the correspondence is arranged alphabetically by sender, letters written by the Commission's secretary, Henry Sackett, and assistant secretary, Edward Hagaman Hall, are filed alphabetically by recipient. This series also contains memoranda sent to members of the Commission.
    - Correspondence: A, 1909 Apr. 16-1909 Nov. 29 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: A, 1909 Dec. 2-1910 Apr. 29 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: A, 1910 May 1-1911 May 26 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: B, 1909 Apr. 15-1909 Aug. 27 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: B, 1909 Sept. 1-1909 Oct. 30 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: B, 1909 Nov. 3-1909 Dec. 14 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: B, 1909 Dec. 17-1911 Jun. 1 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: C, 1908 Oct. 6-1909 Sept. 10 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: C, 1909 Sept. 11-1909 Nov. 15 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: C, 1909 Nov. 16-1910 Feb. 15 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: C, 1910 Feb. 16-1911 May 15 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: D, 1909 Apr. 15-1909 Dec. 30 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: D, 1910 Jan. 5-1911 May 26 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: E, 1909 Apr. 15-1911 Jun. 1 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: F, 1909 May 10-1910 Jan. 28 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: F, 1910 Feb. 1-1911 May 6 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: G, 1909 Apr. 15-1910 Sept. 14 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: G, 1910 Sept. 15-1911 May 13 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: H, 1909 Apr. 15-1909 Sept. 9 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: H, 1909 Sept. 10-1909 Dec. 30 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: H, 1910 Jan. 8-1911 May 27 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: I, 1909 Apr. 16-1910 Mar. 18 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: J, 1909 Apr. 15-1912 Apr. 27 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: K, 1909 Apr. 14-1911 May 29 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: L, 1909 Apr. 15-1909 Aug. 30 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: L, 1909 Sept. 1-1909 Sept. 13 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: L, 1909 Sept. 14-1909 Sept. 27 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: L, 1909 Sept. 28-1909 Dec. 15 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: L, 1909 Dec. 16-1910 Jul. 29 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: L, 1910 Aug. 3-1911 May 24 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: M, 1909 Apr. 15-1909 Jul. 10 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: M, 1909 Jul. 21-1909 Sept. 12 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: M, 1909 Sept. 13-1909 Sept. 30 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: M, 1909 Oct. 2-1909 Oct. 30 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: M, 1909 Nov. 1-1909 Dec. 15 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: M, 1909 Dec. 15-1910 May 30 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: M, 1910 Jun. 1-1911 May 24 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: N, 1909 Apr. 16-1909 Nov. 30 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: N, 1909 Dec. 2-1911 May 27 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: O, 1909 Apr. 15-1911 May 18 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: P, 1909 Apr. 15-1909 Sept. 15 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: P, 1909 Sept. 16-1909 Dec. 29 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: P, 1910 Jan. 5-1911 May 29 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Q, 1909 Apr. 16-1910 Apr. 23 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: R, 1909 Apr. 15-1909 Sept. 30 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: R, 1909 Oct. 1-1909 Nov. 22 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: R, 1909 Nov. 23-1909 Dec. 31 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: R, 1910 Jan, 4-1910 Apr. 29 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: R, 1910 May. 1-1911 May 31 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: S, 1909 Jan. 3-1909 Sept. 15 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: S, 1909 Sept. 16-1909 Oct. 30 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: S, 1909 Nov. 1-1909 Dec. 31 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: S, 1910 Jan. 3-1910 May 31 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: S, 1910 Jun. 1-1911 May 29 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: T, 1909 Apr. 14-1909 Oct. 30 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: T, 1909 Nov. 1-1911 May 31 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: U, 1909 Jun. 11-1911 May 17 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: V, 1909 Apr. 16-1911 Jun. 6 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: W, 1909 May 12-1909 Sept. 6 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: W, 1909 Sept. 7-1909 Sept. 30 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: W, 1909 Oct. 1-1909 Nov. 30 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: W, 1909 Dec. 3-1910 Apr. 30 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: W, 1910 May 1-1911 May 31 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Y, 1909 Apr. 15-1911 Feb. 15 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Z, 1909 Apr. 16-1910 May 19 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence from Assistant Secretary and Secretary with no specified recipient, 1909 Jan. 6-1910 Jun. 10 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 7)
    - Memoranda, circa 1909-1911 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 8)
  - Subseries I.B. Donation Pledges
    This subseries contains letters written by individuals and companies pledging to donate a specified amount of money to the Celebration's subscription fund.
    - List of donations, Undated (Offsite-box 10, Folder 9)
    - Donation Pledges: A, 1909 May 21-1909 Sept. 27 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 10)
    - Donation Pledges: B, 1909 May 17-1909 Sept. 27 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1)
    - Donation Pledges: C, 1909 May 18-1909 Sept. 27 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 2)
    - Donation Pledges: D, 1909 May 24-1909 Sept. 23 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 3)
    - Donation Pledges: E, 1909 May 21-1909 Sept. 23 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 4)
    - Donation Pledges: F, 1909 May 8-1909 Sept. 23 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5)
    - Donation Pledges: G, 1909 May 18-1909 Nov. 8 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6)
    - Donation Pledges: H, 1909 May 24-1909 Sept. 28 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 7)
    - Donation Pledges: I, 1909 June 24-1909 Sept. 22 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 8)
    - Donation Pledges: J, 1909 May 22-1909 Oct. 29 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 9)
    - Donation Pledges: K, 1909 May 18-1909 Sept. 22 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 10)
    - Donation Pledges: L, 1909 May 19-1909 Sept. 27 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 11)
    - Donation Pledges: M, 1909 May 19-1909 Sept. 24 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
    - Donation Pledges: N, 1909 May 18-1909 Sept. 22 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 2)
    - Donation Pledges: O, 1909 May 21-1909 Oct. 13 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 3)
    - Donation Pledges: P, 1909 May 18-1909 Nov. 5 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 4)
    - Donation Pledges: R, 1909 May 18-1909 Sept. 23 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 5)
    - Donation Pledges: S, 1909 May 18-1909 Jul. 30 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 6)
    - Donation Pledges: S, 1909 Aug. 2-1910 May 19 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7)
    - Donation Pledges: T, 1909 May 18-1909 Nov. 3 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 8)
    - Donation Pledges: U, 1909 May 18-1909 Sept. 20 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 9)
    - Donation Pledges: V, 1909 May 19-1909 Sept. 28 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 10)
    - Donation Pledges: W, 1909 May 20-1909 Sept. 28 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 11)
    - Donation Pledges: Y, 1909 Jun. 24-1909 Sept. 15 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1)
    - Donation Pledges: Z, 1909 Jun. 25-1909 Sept. 10 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 2)
  - Subseries I.C. Invitation Responses
    This subseries consists of replies to the various events sponsored by the Commission, as well as thank you letters commending the Commission on a job well done. Most of the individuals invited to the Celebration and banquets were dignitaries and officials from the United States, as well as countries throughout the world.
    - Invitation Responses, A-N, 1909 Sep-1909 Nov. (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3)
    - Invitation Responses, P-V, 1909 Sep-1909 Nov. (Offsite-box 13, Folder 4)
    - Acceptances for Astor Hotel Banquet, 1909 Sept. (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5)
    - Acceptances for Astor Hotel Banquet, 1909 Sept. (Offsite-box 13, Folder 6)
    - Acceptances for Astor Hotel Banquet, 1909 Sept. (Offsite-box 13, Folder 7)
    - Acceptances for Astor Hotel Banquet, 1909 Sept. (Offsite-box 13, Folder 8)
    - Acceptances for Astor Hotel Banquet, 1909 Sept. (Offsite-box 13, Folder 9)
    - Regrets for Astor Hotel Banquet, 1909 Sept. (Offsite-box 13, Folder 10)
    - Acceptances for Governor's Island banquet, 1909 Sept. (Offsite-box 13, Folder 11)
    - Acceptances for Governor's Island banquet, 1909 Sept. (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1)
    - Regrets for Governor's Island banquet, 1909 Sept. (Offsite-box 14, Folder 2)
    - Acceptances for Metropolitan Opera House banquet, 1909 Sept. (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3)
    - Thank you letters: Foreign countries, A-M, 1909 Oct.-1910 Feb. (Offsite-box 14, Folder 4)
    - Thank you letters: Foreign countries, A-M, 1909 Oct.-1910 Feb. (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5)
    - Thank you letters: United States (includes letter from President Taft), 1909 Oct.-1909 Dec. (Offsite-box 14, Folder 6)
  - Subseries I.D. Acknowledgements
    This subseries contains acknowledgements sent to the Commission confirming receipt of The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission.
    - Acknowledgements confirming receipt of The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission, 1909, 1911 May (Offsite-box 14, Folder 7)
    - Acknowledgements confirming receipt of The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission, 1910, 1911 May (Offsite-box 14, Folder 8)
    - Acknowledgements confirming receipt of The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission, 1911, 1911 May-1911 Jul. (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1)
    - Acknowledgements confirming receipt of The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission, 1912, 1911 May-1911 Jul. (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2)
    - Acknowledgements confirming receipt of The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission, 1913, 1911 May-1911 Sept. (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
    - Acknowledgements confirming receipt of The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission, 1914, 1911 May-1911 Sept. (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)
    - Acknowledgements confirming receipt of The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission, 1915, 1911 May-1911 Sept. (Offsite-box 15, Folder 5)
    - Acknowledgements confirming receipt of The Fourth Annual Report of the Hudson Fulton Celebration Commission, 1916, 1911 May 16-1911 Oct. 24 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 6)
- Series II: Financial Documents
  - Subseries II.A. Cancelled Checks
    This subseries consists of cancelled checks written by the Commission to individuals and organizations. Once again, the funding source is noted by the folder title. This suberies also contains checkbook registers for the various fund accounts. The checks are arranged by check number.
    - Astor Trust Company, 1909 Nov. 8-1910 Apr. 25 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1)
    - Funded by the Subscription Fund, 1-300, 1909 Mar. 22-1909 Dec. 1 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 2)
    - Funded by the Subscription Fund, 301-604, 1909 Dec. 1-1911 Dec. 7 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 3)
    - Funded by Chapter 325 of the Laws of 1906, 1-130, 1906 Oct. 20-1909 Jan. 29 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 4)
    - Funded by Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 1-100, 1909 Jan. 22-1909 Apr. 6 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 5)
    - Funded by Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 101-400, 1909 Apr. 6-1909 Aug. 24 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 6)
    - Funded by Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, 401-429, 1909 Aug. 12-1910 Sept. 27 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 7)
    - Funded by Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 1-300, 1909 Aug. 14-1909 Oct. 15 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 8)
    - Funded by Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 301-600, 1909 Oct. 15-1909 Nov. 24 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 9)
    - Funded by Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 601-800, 1909 Nov. 24-1909 Dec. 3 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 1)
    - Funded by Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, 801-972, 1909 Dec. 3-1910 Jan. 3 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 2)
    - Funded by Chapter 811 of the Laws of 1911, 1-2, 1911 Dec. 16 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 3)
    - Checkbook register: Funded by Chapter 325 of the Laws of 1906 check #1-30, 1906 Oct. 20-1909 Jan. 29 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 4)
    - Checkbook register: Astor Trust Company, check #1-291, 1909 Nov. 8-1910 Apr. 5 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 1)
    - Checkbook register: Subscription Fund, check #A1-A9, 1906 Apr. 30-1906 Sept. 17 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 2)
    - Checkbook register: Subscription Fund, check #A10-141, 1906 Oct. 20-1909 Oct. 6 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 3)
    - Checkbook register: Subscription Fund, check #142-441, 1909 Oct. 15-1910 Feb. 3 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 4)
    - Checkbook register: Subscription Fund, check #442-847, 1909 Feb. 3-1912 Jun. 29 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 5)
    - Checkbook register: Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, check #1-231, 1909 Jan. 22-1909 Jun. 14 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 6)
    - Checkbook register: Chapter 466 of the Laws of 1908, check #232-429, 1909 Jun. 14-1909 Sept. 27 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 7)
    - Checkbook register: Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, check #1-199, 1909 Aug. 14-1909 Oct. 16 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 8)
    - Checkbook register: Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, check #200-410, 1909 Oct. 29-1909 Nov. 3 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 9)
    - Checkbook register: Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, check #411-608, 1909 Nov. 3-1909 Nov. 24 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 10)
    - Checkbook register: Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, check #609-811, 1909 Nov. 24-1909 Dec. 6 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 11)
    - Checkbook register: Chapter 448 of the Laws of 1909, check #812-1044, 1909 Dec. 6-1910 Jan. 3 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 12)
    - Checkbook register: Chapter 811 of the Laws of 1911, check #1-3, 1911 Dec. 16 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 13)
  - Subseries II.B. General Financial Documents
    This subseries contains all other financial documents related to the operation of the Commission, such as account sheets, ledgers, cashbooks, payroll records, and audit reports.
    - Financial documents, 1909 Sept. 24-1911 Feb. 15 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 5)
    - Account sheets for Metal Fund, 1909 Sept. 30-1909 Nov. 22 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 6)
    - Account sheets for State Fund, 1909 Mar. 27-1910 Feb. 25 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 7)
    - Account sheets for Subscription Fund, 1909 Jun. 30-1912 Sept. 24 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 8)
    - Accounts, 1909 Sept. 20-1909 Oct. 18 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 9)
    - Accounts: Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1909 Jan. 9-1910 Jan. 7 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 10)
    - Accounts: Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1909 Jan. 9-1910 Jan. 7 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 11)
    - Accounts: Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1909 Jan. 9-1909 Jan. 7 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 12)
    - Accounts: Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1909 Jan. 9-1910 Jan. 7 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 1)
    - Accounts: Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1909 Jan. 9-1910 Jan. 7 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 2)
    - Accounts: Whitehead & Hoag Co., 1910 May 14-1910 Jan. 7 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 3)
    - Appropriations ledger, 1906-1909 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 4)
    - Appropriations ledger, 1906-1910 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 5)
    - Bills and receipts, 1909 Oct. 12-1911 May 24 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 6)
    - Bills and receipts: American District Telegraph Company, 1909 Nov. 1-1911 May 26 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 7)
    - Audit report for the period of 1905 Dec. 5-1912 Jun. 30, 1912 Oct. 3 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 8)
    - Ledger, 1906 Sept. 26-1906 Sept. 28 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 9)
    - Payroll records, 1909 Jan. 30-1909 Feb. 6 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 10)
    - Payroll records, 1909 Sept. 18-1909 Oct. 23 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 11)
    - Sale records, Undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder 11)
    - Treasurer's reports and financial estimates, 1910 Mar. 1-1910 Aug. 19 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 13)
    - Audit report, 1909 Apr. 5 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 14)
    - Cashbook, 1905 Dec. 28-1909 Feb. 22 (Offsite-box 38, Volume 15)
    - Cashbook, 1905 Dec. 28-1909 May 1 (Offsite-box 39, Volume 16)
    - Cashbook, 1906 Sept. 28-1909 Dec. 13 (Offsite-box 39, Volume 17)
    - Cashbook, 1906 Sept-1910 Feb (Offsite-box 39, Volume 18)
    - Cashbook, 1909 Dec. 13-1911 Dec. 16 (Offsite-box 39, Volume 19)
    - Cashbook: City Fund, 1909 Aug. 23-1911 Apr. 27 (Offsite-box 40, Volume 20)
    - Cashbook: Subscription Fund, 1905 Dec. 28-1910 Jul. 16 (Offsite-box 40, Volume 21)
    - Ledger, circa 1908-1910 (Offsite-box 40, Volume 22)
    - Ledger: Bands, circa 1909 (Offsite-box 40, Volume 23)
    - Ledger: Bands, circa 1909 (Offsite-box 40, Volume 24)
    - Ledger: Subscription Fund, 1910 Jul. 21-1912 Jun. 30 (Offsite-box 40, Volume 25)
  - Subseries II.C. Committee Financial Documents
    This subseries contains the financial documents, such as account sheets, for specific committees.
    - Aquatic Sports Committee, 1909 Sept. 17-1909 Nov. 18 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 14)
    - Badge, Flag, and Poster Committee, 1909 Aug. 31-1909 Oct. 20 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 15)
    - Children's Festivals Committee, 1909 Jul. 1-1910 Feb. 15 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 16)